// flashcards/acperformance.js
export const acperformance = [
	{ front: "V<sub>REF</sub>", back: "Reference Speed, Final Approach/Landing Speed" },
	{ front: "V<sub>MCA</sub>", back: "Minimum Controllable Airborne Speed<br>(with 1 engine inoperative)" },
	{ front: "V<sub>MCG</sub>", back: "Nosewheel Steering (rudder control is ineffective)<br>Minimum Controllable Ground Speed" },
	{ front: "V<sub>2</sub>", back: "Takeoff Safety Speed<br>(Aircraft can safely remain airborne after leaving ground effect)" },
	{ front: "V<sub>SO</sub>", back: "Landing Configuration Stall Speed<br>(Dirty - Flaps/Slats and Landing Gear Extended)" },
	{ front: "V<sub>LOF</sub>", back: "Liftoff Speed" },
	{ front: "V<sub>1</sub>", back: "Takeoff Decision Speed" },
	{ front: "V<sub>S</sub>", back: "Stall Speed<br>(Clean - Flaps/Slats and Landing Gear Tucked in)" },
	{ front: "V<sub>FTO</sub>", back: "Final Takeoff Speed" },
	{ front: "V<sub>MU</sub>", back: "Minimum Unstick Speed" },
	{ front: "V<sub>R</sub>", back: "Rotation Speed<br>(Pitching the nose up)" },
	{ front: "V<sub>A</sub>", back: "In Air Maneuvering Speed<br>(Maximum speed the AC can be controlled with the rudder in the air)<br>Never go full 'rudder'" },
	{ front: "AC PACKs on or off for takeoff performance?", back: "Off" },
	{ front: "What runway measurement is V<sub>1</sub> based on?", back: "ASDA<br>(Accelerate Stop Distance Available)" },
	{ front: "How much additional runway is required to stop an aircraft on a non-grooved wet runway?", back: "115% of the distance required for a dry runway<br>(60% Dry * 1.15)" },
	{ front: "What runway measurement is V<sub>2</sub> based on?", back: "TODA<br>(Takeoff Distance Available)" },
	{ front: "How do you Calculate V<sub>REF</sub>?", back: "130% of your landing configuration stall speed equals Reference Speed<p>(V<sub>SO</sub> x 1.3 = V<sub>REF</sub>)</p>" },
	{ front: "What are some factors that affect aircraft takeoff performance?<br>Think: WARMATE FC", back: "<ul><li><b>W</b>ind (Headwind = Better)</li><li><b>A</b>ltimeter (Higher Density = Better)</li><li><b>R</b>unway Slope (Downslope = Better)</li><li><b>M</b>ELs/CDLs (None = Better)</li><li><b>A</b>irport Elevation (Lower = Better)</li><li><b>T</b>empature (Colder = Better)</li><li><b>E</b>ngine Bleeds (Off = Better)</li><li><b>F</b>laps (Extended = Better, More Lift!)</li><li><b>C</b>ontaminations (No snow, water = Better)</li></ul>" },
	{ front: "Do you want engine bleeds on or off for takeoff?", back: "Off<br>(More air for the engine)" },
	{ front: "Higher or Lower Pressure for takeoff?", back: "Higher<br>(More Dense Air)" },
	{ front: "What wind direction is better for takeoff?<br>Headwind or Tailwind", back: "Headwind<br>(Less Ground Speed required for takeoff)" },
	{ front: "What wind direction is better for landing?<br>Headwind or Tailwind", back: "Headwind" },
	{ front: "What wind direction is better enroute?<br>Headwind or Tailwind", back: "Tailwind<br>(Higher Ground Speed)" },
	{ front: "What is better for takeoff - Flaps/Slats Extended or Retracted?", back: "Extended<br>(More Lift!)" },
	{ front: "What temperature is better for takeoff - Higher or Lower?", back: "Lower<br>(Colder = More Dense)" },
	{ front: "What airport elevation is better for takeoff - Higher or Lower?", back: "Lower" },
	{ front: "What is better for takeoff - Upslope or Downslope Runway?", back: "Downslope<br>(More Speed)" },
	{ front: "What is better for takeoff - Dry or Wet Runway?", back: "Dry" },
	{ front: "What is better for Landing - Dry or Wet Runway?", back: "Dry" },
];